Armed of the transfers convolution,
you're now ready to dive into
the details of the unit architecture.
In this video, let's first go
over the architecture quickly to
build intuition about how the unit works.
And in the next video,
we'll go through the details together.
Let's dig in.
Here's a rough diagram of
the neural network architecture
for semantic segmentation.
And so we use normal convolutions for
the first part of the neural network.
And similar to the earlier neural
networks that you've seen.
This part of the neural network
will sort of compress the image.
You've gone from a very large image
to one where the heightened whiff
of this activation is much smaller.
So you've lost a lot of spatial
information because the dimension is much
smaller, but it's much deeper.
So, for example, this middle layer
may represent that looks like
there's a cat roughly in the lower
right hand portion of the image.
But the detailed spatial
information is lost because
of heightened with is much smaller.
Then the second half of this neural
network uses the transports convolution
to blow the representation size up back
to the size of the original input image.
Now it turns out that there's one
modification to this architecture that
would make it work much better.
And that's what we turn this into
the unit architecture, which is
that skip connections from the earlier
layers to the later layers like this.
So that this earlier block of activations
is copied directly to this later block.
So why do we want to do this?
It turns out that for this, next final
layer to decide which region is a cat.
Two types of information are useful.
One is the high level, spatial,
high level contextual information which
it gets from this previous layer.
Where hopefully the neural network,
we have figured out that in the lower
right hand corner of the image or
maybe in the right part of the image,
there's some cat like stuff going on.
But what is missing is a very detailed,
fine grained spatial information.
Because this set of activations
here has lower spatial
resolution to heighten with is just lower.
So what the skip connection does is it
allows the neural network to take this
very high resolution, low level feature
information where it could capture for
every pixel position, how much
fairy stuff is there in this pixel?
And used to skip connection to pause
that directly to this later layer.
And so this way this layer has both
the lower resolution, but high level,
spatial, high level contextual
information, as well as the low level.
But more detailed texture like
information in order to make
a decision as to whether a certain
pixel is part of a cat or not.
In this video, you saw just a brief,
high level intuition about how unit works.
Let's go on to the next video to see
the details of how you can implement it.